# Anthony Alaribe, Programmer and Solutions Architect

anthonyalaribe@gmail.com | 2348161115653 | Calabar, Nigeria, NG http://twitter.com/tonyalaribe | http://facebook.com/35sympaty

**SUMMARY** 

With over seven years of experience as a Full Stack Developer, my commitment is to blur the line between secure, well tested and designed apps, whether for the web, desktop, microprocessors or mobile. My specialty is in the automation of applications to work with as little management and resources as possible.

**EXPERIENCE** 

### Shop440, Co Founder

2017-01-03 — Present

shop440.com

- o A platform that makes it possible to for buyers to shop for items from sellers in their cities.
- o Mongo DB
- o Analytics
- o Golang
- o React is
- o Amazon Web Services

## **Entrenet, Consulting Developer**

2016-11-07 — Present

entrenet.org.ng

- Entrenet is a network marketting platform, developed for Investlift limited. The platform was
  written on top of graph database technologies, making the platform able to scale to large
  concurrent users, with little server resources. The admin dashboard is written in react js and
  golang, and features a genealogy system, alongside payment verifications and analytics by an
  admin.
- Cayley graph db
- o Analytics
- Golang
- React js
- Amazon Web Services

## Calabar Yellow Pages , Consulting Developer

2016-01-08 — Present

http://calabarpages.com

- o Calabar Yellow Pages is the leading business directory listing service in Cross River State, with over 3000 businesses currently listed on the site. My role was the design and implementation of the system, including the database structure, REST API, Front end (React js) and payment processor integration. As well as the management dashboard, including analytics and SHA 256 encrypted Json Web Token based security, and web payment using the Interswitch payment gateway.
- o Clean User Interface
- o Analytics
- Golang
- React js
- MONGODB

http://donehire.com

- DoneHire Global is a Delaware C-corp based in San Jose California. The company provides an
  innovative social approach to recruiting, with clients including large globa companies such as
  Synaptics. I serve as the Technical co founder at the moment, and have been involved in the
  development and launch of flicto, which now has parters in 10 countries, including Nigeria via
  flicto.com.ng.
- o Rethink DB
- o Analytics
- Golang
- o React is
- o Amazon Web Services

## VisaExpress Travel Club, Consulting Developer

2016-01-08 — Present

http://visaexpresstravel.club

- o VisaExpress Travel is a restricted membership club, with very well known and respected members from the all over the country. I was involved in design and implementation of their web presence, which includes a carefully crafted front end, and a feature packed backend, that lets members keep track of travel packages and dates, while communicating with each other, and also maintaining a centralised gallery of Pictures from their travels. The system also automatically generates the details that are used in printing a Credit Card (Thanks to Interswitch), which can be used by members at stores and ATMs all over the world.
- o Clean User Interface
- o Analytics
- Golang
- o React is
- Security
- o Landing page design

## Pro Earth Realty Services, Consulting Developer

2015-08-22 — 2016-01-3

http://proearth.com.ng

- Pro Earth Realty is a real estate and property listing Company, based out of Cross River State. I
  was contracted for the development and management of the landing end, Property listing end
  and the management dashboard for their online platform.
- o Clean User Interface
- Analytics
- o Golang
- o Angular JS
- o Mongo DB

### **Oddjobz Services, Consulting Developer**

2016-03-22 - 2016-06-30

http://oddjobz.com.ng

- Oddjobz is platform for finding artisans in an area. My role was the implemtation and management of the frontend system and backend, with careful care given to user interaction and analytics.
- o Clean User Interface
- Analytics
- Golang
- o Angular JS
- o Mongo DB

- Digital forte is a rising software company, producing solutions for businesses around Nigeria.
   At Digital Forte, I was involved in reimplementing their homegrown school management system(edna), in modern technologies. The end product was a more modern system that was easier to deploy to customers and cheaper to run. The system was migrated from a monolithic C# MVC application to a golang and angular js Application that runs on as little as 15mb of ram on the server.
- o Clean User Interface
- Analytics
- Golang
- o Angular js

## **Grand Central, Platform Developer (Server and Web Client)**

2015-10-05 - 2016-10-27

http://infographicsnigeria.com/

- Grand Central is one of the top IT companies in Africa, consulting for multiple governments and Companies, including the Cross River State Government. I was involved in the development of the pluslife mesh communication software. A software that lets users make calls and chat, with no internet connection, over bluetooth and wifi mesh networks.
- o Clean User Interface
- o Analytics
- o Go mobile
- Android NDK
- o Systems Programming

## Kaku.com.ng, Lead Developer

2014-02-08 — 2015-05-27

http://kaku.com.ng

- I developed the frontend and backend of kaku.com.ng, which is a platform that lets users discover places to hangout on a budget. Kaku is currently a failed startup, but a self hosted version is available at http://kaku-go.herokuapp.com.
- o Clean User Interface
- o Analytics
- o golang

#### Pacific College, Web Development Teacher

2013-02-08 - 2014-05-01

- Pacific computer college is one of the top ICT training colleges in Cross River State, training individuals on a variety of fields from Accounting packages like peach tree, to Web design and programming.
- Trained students on Web Animations with CSS3
- o Trained students on MVC web application design using javascript

## AWARDS

## 2nd Position NASA space apps challenge, NASA

2015-02-27

My team came second in the NASA space apps challenge in Cross River State, which was held
at the IDEA hub. We created an app that lets anyone control a computer from anywhere in the
world, with just their cell phone. The cell phone acts as a mouse and keyboard, with support for
voice controls.

#### VOLUNTEERING

#### Enactus, Volunteer

2012-01-01 — 2015-05-27

http://enactus.org

- An international organization of students who are using entrepreneurship to make the world a better place
- I rose to become the team's Project Manager
- o Designed the Enactus University of Calabar Website
- Headed the online FCMB e-challenge that won the team a trip to china

**EDUCATION** 

**University of Calabar** 

2011-01-01 — 2016-10-01

Bachelor of Medical Laboratory Science - Medical Laboratory Science	

**SKILLS** 

**Web Development:** HTML 5, CSS, Javascript, Backbone js, Angular js, React js, Bootstrap, SASS, LESS, Tachyons.io

**Backend Development:** Golang, PHP, Python, Node js, Linux shell, Mongo db, Rethink DB, Redis, SQL, Cayley Graph Database, Schema.org and Freebase, Amazon Web Services, Linux Cloud Server Management

**Artificial Intelligence:** Natural language processing (NLTK), Open Computer Vision (openCV), Chatbot programming (Chatscript), Speech Recognition and Synthesis (Festival lite and CMU Sphinx)

LANGUAGES

English (Native speaker)